Prince Gadiel has arrived.
Oh? You're looking better than I expected.
As Rovel and the others aren't with you,
I presume they saw right through me.
What a shame.
You have my praise
for returning with the medicine.
However, you do understand this was
a gesture of Ellen's kindness, don't you?
Yes.
Father...
Father, did you use me as one of your pawns?!
What makes you think so?
You ordered your subordinates to kidnap
a daughter of the Vankreift family,
then sent me to procure
medicine from their domain!
All to ensure I'd cross paths with them!
I have a message from Ellen.
"You will regret ever touching
my family," she said.
I see.
She also said to never again
make contact with the Vankreifts—
That this is their final warning.
It seems I've angered Ellen.
Guard!
Inform the gatekeepers that entry
to the royal capital is now restricted!
Gather all the healers in the country!
At once!
The queen and my sons will evacuate!
I cannot have them stay here!
Yes, sire!
I have made an enemy of the Vankreifts.
The royal family will now face retribution.
I misread Ellen.
I assumed she was softhearted
and underestimated her.
Is this all the medicine?
Yes.
I-If I may...
Th-This is far from enough
to treat everyone in the country.
King Ravisel has taken us too lightly.
After all he's done, do not think
for a moment you will have our aid.
We've been given little medicine.
The royal capital will soon be flooded
with patients and fall into chaos.
We have no choice but to restrict entry.
However, this could breed
resentment and lead to riots.
Well, this will serve as a test for you.
Your Majesty.
I shall stay here with you.
Very well. You've truly grown strong.
BETWEEN HUMANS AND SPIRITS
Even if you wish to stay in this country,
we cannot guarantee your lives.
The royal family already
has their eye on you.
Of course, we will not
allow you safe harbor here.
Especially after all you've done to Rafilia.
Hmph! So what?
If you do as I'm about to say,
we'll let you live.
Let's hear it.
Spread word that the royal family has
seized all of what little medicine remained
from the treatment center
in the Vankreift domain.
Spread that rumor, and we'll assist you
in fleeing the country.
Fine.
Much obliged.
Please see them off the property.
Yes, milady.
Oh, and please don't get any funny ideas.
The spirit queen is always
watching over you, after all.
Move it.
If the king handles this poorly,
the royal family is sure to perish.
Well, I'm sure with Mr. Blackheart,
they'll be just fine.
Ellen...
We mustn't forgive them. It will only
make the royal family arrogant.
Yes, but this is...
Uncle.
Please restrict entry into our domain.
Tell any new patients that our medicine
was taken by the royal family.
Also, please spread word that Father and I
have gone to gather medicinal ingredients.
We plan on returning
to the spirit world for a while.
What?
Don't worry.
I'll still bring medicine enough
for our domain.
How do you intend on dealing
with the royal family?
I informed His Highness that the crown
must pay for any further medicine we provide.
I want him to reflect on his mistake, though,
so we won't supply any for a while yet.
Ellen...
Thank you, Ellen.
Hey, what's goin' on?
Is it true that the royal
family took the medicine?
Yes, it is.
Please, I beg you!
All because my daughter was
kidnapped...
I'm sorry!
Please raise your head, Your Grace.
Do something about this!
What the heck is the royal family thinking?!
Please do something about this!
Yeah, that's right.
The royal family snatched up every last bit
of medicine from the Vankreifts'
treatment center.
You're kidding!
I heard it directly from the
people working there.
There's no doubt about it.
Then the royal family is...
Hoarding it all for themselves, I'm sure!
What the heck?
I hear the royal family
is hoarding the medicine.
All when the disease is spreading!
What in the world is the royal family thinking?
What are we supposed to do?
They're just trying to save themselves.
What a cowardly thing to do!
It's all the royal family's fault!
The royal family is to blame!
Yeah, the royal family!
Hand over the medicine!
The royals!
We have no medicine here.
Lies! Hand it over!
It has to be somewhere!
Hand over the medicine!
We know it's here!
Don't be rough with them.
Understood.
Your Majesty!
Those who are ill are gathering
at the castle seeking medicine.
Open the treatment centers
on the castle grounds.
Send in the court healers as well.
They're all demanding
that we hand over the medicine...
We have no medicine to give them,
but treat them as best you can.
Sire.
But a drop in the ocean, is it not?
Ellen, dear...
Mother.
This must be so hard for you.
But you made the right decision, my dear Ellen.
Mr. Blackheart is to blame
for taking it all too far.
You have no right to do this!
This is horrible!
Hey! Say something!
Stop messing with us!
I...
In order to make clear the positions
of the royal family and the spirits,
I have done all I could
for the sake of our future.
So why does my heart...
You are my pride and joy.
My kind, smart, darling daughter.
Mother!
I'm sorry for placing you in the middle
between humans and spirits.
However, there are times when
one must be ruthless.
You understand that, don't you?
I understand. I do understand. But...
Hand over the medicine you're hiding!
You're gonna leave us to die?!
I knew it. We can't quell
the riots without medicine.
Your Highness! Permission to report!
The messenger we sent to the
Vankreift family has returned!
And the medicine?
They said that Lord Rovel is away gathering
ingredients for the medicine
and thus could not negotiate.
I see.
What is going on?
What is this ingredient?
Did you figure it out?
No.
The princess doesn't smile much anymore.
Oh, Van.
I know. I'm worrying everyone.
She laughed!
The princess laughed!
She laughed, she laughed!
She laughed, yay!
Hey!
Oh yeah?!
Tickle, tickle, tickle, tickle,
tickle, tickle, tickle, tickle!
Oh, Van. Goodness!
You finally smiled, my princess.
A smile really does suit
you best, Ellen, dear.
Father, Mother...
I'm sorry, Father! Mother!
You know, Ori and I were just
saying that maybe this is enough.
This incident has dealt him a hard blow.
Yet here you regret your decision.
This had to be done
in order to corner the king.
Still, it pains you to sow discontent
among the people
and to see them in anguish,
doesn't it, Ellen?
Yes.
You really are kind, Ellen.
Up until now, I thought the only people
important to me were you and Ori.
I'd fallen into despair after
witnessing man's true nature.
But you know what, Ellen?
I managed to remember something.
How I felt long ago.
That's all thanks to you, Ellen.
Seeing how deeply you care for my mother,
Sauvel, and the rest of the Vankreift family,
I remembered why I risked my life to protect
people during the Monster Tempest.
You are daughter to us both, so it's only
natural that you cherish both sides.
Father, Mother...
Your Majesty!
Someone! Anyone! Summon the healer!
Your Majesty! Please hang in there!
Your Majesty!
Hurry!
The people are suffering!
Even if it's just food supplies,
deliver them with haste—
Your Highness!
Are you all right?!
Your Highness, please do not push yourself!
Please go rest.
Where's the medicine?
There isn't any left.
How can that be?
I have a report saying
it was all used up in experiments
trying to figure out how to reproduce it.
My word...
Have you wasted
all of the medicine I gave you?
It certainly appears that way.
Lord Rovel the hero?
I should have sent someone
who was familiar with the process.
This is why we told you
you weren't capable of making it.
Goodness me. How rare to see
His Majesty in bed.
Father, that's not appropriate.
Could it be...
Might this young lady here
be the Healing Princess?
P-Please!
I beg of you, give us the medicine!
That's the first thing out of his mouth, huh?
Well, I suppose with
His Majesty in this state...
But are you sure about this?
We are technically trespassing, after all.
Well...
I suppose if you kick us out now,
you'd never get the medicine you need.
Very well then.
These two are separate medicines.
Administer one pill of each three
times a day, and give them together.
Y-Yes, ma'am!
Th-Thank you so much!
L-Lord Rovel, you have my gratitude
from the bottom of my heart!
If you're grateful, thank Ellen.
Don't play with it this time.
This was the right thing to do, right?
Well, he's certainly suffering
some consequences.
Father...
All right then!
I'm going to go deliver medicine
to Sauvel right now.
I'll tell him to start accepting patients
a little at a time from outside our land.
Yes. Please do.
You go take a break, Ellen.
Father, I'm sorry.
I have an errand to run myself.
How are you feeling, Your Highness?
Ellen!
Am I... dreaming?
Your Highness, don't you think this situation
is similar to the Monster Tempest
from two hundred years ago?
She's right. Back then it was monsters,
and now we face a epidemic.
We're drowning in fear, and again,
trying to rely on the spirits' power.
Do you think things may have been different
if the royal family and the spirits
had spoken beforehand like this back then?
At the very least, I don't
think the royal family would have
resorted to such cruel
treatment of the spirits.
We wanted you spirits so badly.
The power of the spirits,
the power that name brings...
Every time we tried to take it by force,
we ended up hurting you.
And even now—
We will monitor the disease
so that it does not spread any further.
Just a moment ago, we delivered
medicine to your court healer.
You did? Thank you!
Once you recover, let us discuss
our future dealings, Your Highness.
You'd allow us to negotiate with you?
That said, we will be driving
a hard bargain. Is that understood?
Yes, of course.
Hey, Ellen?
What is it?
If... If I'm able to gain your trust,
even if it's just a little at a time...
Can we talk like this again?
It'd be a conversation
held at this distance...
I don't mind! Even then!
That'll be all for today.
I'll be back another time with my father.
All right.
Take care, Your Highness.
Princess.
Oh, Van!
Did something happen?
Huh? Like what?
Your face is red.
What?!
Did something good happen?
N-No, nothing!
Maybe it's because I'm sleepy.
Oh, is that so?
Maybe it's because the
unsettling feeling that's been
building inside of me has
completely cleared away...
I asked Sauvel to resume treatment
within the Vankreift domain.
Also, I had them spread the word
that we're ready to accept patients.
Very good. Then let us get to work.
Princess.
You called?
There's something I'd like
to ask the both of you to do.
First, Leben, I would like you to restore
the physical strength of all the
patients within the Vankreift territory
and increase their natural healing ability.
I'd be happy to.
Krelen, I'd like you to treat the
seriously ill patients amongst them.
Understood.
Now, let us bring back everyone's smiles!
Off we go!
I asked the two of them to make sure the
recovery from the illness appeared natural.
But since it could lead to a riot,
I had the spirits put up
a barrier to trigger their magic
when a patient enters our domain.
Furthermore, to heal the land
neglected due to the disease,
I first refined nitrogen, phosphorus,
potassium, magnesium,
and calcium to serve as fertilizer.
I then had Borden the earth spirit
spread it evenly over the fields.
With action from the rain spirits,
Niesel and Regen,
the light spirit, Licht,
and the plant spirits, Fran and Opst,
our crops grew abundant in no time.
To help the struggling citizens,
Uncle Sauvel issued a decree
allowing them to pay their taxes
in crops for a time.
The harvested produce
was then distributed to the needy.
And as for the money the domain needed,
we earned it by selling
medicine to the royal family.
No, I'm afraid I cannot accept that price.
Duke Sauvel, you truly are
skilled at driving a bargain.
After repeating this cycle for some time,
the epidemic eventually subsided.
And then...
Is that true?!
Yes, there has been a massive influx of
people to the Vankreift domain.
Thanks to their bountiful fields,
our farmers were always shorthanded,
which brought people flocking to the area.
More people brought merchants,
which brought life back to the town.
Thanks to all this,
the Vankreift domain has become known
as the most livable place in the country.
To think they managed to use the epidemic
to develop their own territory...
Do you finally understand, Your Majesty?
Rovel.
I believe I told you before—
You have no chance of winning against Ellen.
So be it.
From now on, the royal family
will make no overture to Ellen.
I swear by it.
You seem to be feeling a lot better.
Yes, all because of the medicine.
I thank you.
Tch, what kind of a reply is that?
This is no fun at all.
Fluffy!
You worked so hard, princess.
Fluff away all you like!
Thank you, Van! Fluffy, fluffy, fluff, fluff!
She really managed to do it all.
My sweet Ellen is the best!
She loves all spirits and humans alike.
She's proving through her very
existence that we can
mutually understand and support one another.
My daughter is amazing.
Yes, of course she is!
Father! Mother!
Let's go see everyone in the
Vankreift family right now!
Translation: Yukari Murase-Louden
Editing: Riley Dalton
Quality Check: Ashley Barboza
Translation Check: Elizabeth Ellis